(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T20:56:14.869803",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
歪んでいる闇を割って
Shatter the distorted darkness,
その中の濁みを打て
and strike the turbidity within.
計算と保守
Calculation and maintenance,
自分勝手なルール
selfish rules,
歪んでいる事実
distorted facts,
期待を消却して
eliminating expectations.
向かうべき未来の目
The eyes of the future we must face,
摘んでいる正体
plucking out their true nature—
探し出して
go find them.
その手を掴んで
Grab that hand
光の差す明日へ 影も連れてく
and head to tomorrow's light, bringing your shadow too.
きっと冷たくて暗い雨だって
I'm sure even if it's a cold and dark rain,
誰か救っているから
someone is saving us,
平行線を繋げば環になる
so connecting parallel lines makes a ring,
光に変えて
turning it into light.
音を立てて ずれいく世界
Making a sound, a world drifting apart,
SOSの群れ 僕を消耗して
a swarm of SOS exhausts me.
音を立てて ずれいく世界
Making a sound, a world drifting apart,
SOSの群れ 僕を消耗して
a swarm of SOS exhausts me.
近すぎてボヤけた 現実と未来
Reality and future blurred by being too close,
まだ手を伸ばせる 答えを探して
I can still reach out, searching for the answer.
向かうべき未来の目 その中 耳を澄ませば
The eyes of the future we must face—if you listen closely within,
まだ見ぬ世界に 光を祈って 待っている
praying for light in a world yet unseen, waiting.
不安もそっと抱いて
Softly holding onto our unease,
きっといつか疲れて すべてを消してしまいたくなっても
I'm sure even if you get tired someday and want to erase everything,
君の声が僕を呼び戻す
your voice will call me back.
ほらよく見てみれば 風向き少し変われば晴れる
Look closely, if the wind changes direction a bit, it clears up.
矢印の方へ それが示す明日へ
Toward the arrow, toward the tomorrow it points to.
灯がひとつ 灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on and on,
天を彩った霓が綺麗だ
coloring the heavens so beautifully.
僕の吐いた白い息のように 消してしまえたらな
If only I could erase it like my breath in the cold air...
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Suppressed and deeply sunken,
泣き声さえ 聴こえているから
even my crying voice can still be heard.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も 僕の青色で塗り潰して
Paint over your piercing anxiety and pain with my blue...
全部涙になって 星の海を流れていたんだ
turning them all into tears flowing through the sea of stars.
果てしなく闇の中に そっと青を添えたら、ほら
If you gently add blue into the endless darkness, look—
流星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
a shooting star flew right above my head,
誰もない夜の空を染めた
dyeing the deserted night sky.
深く寝静まった街の中へ 降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sorrow is pouring down into the deeply sleeping town?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ もやのかかった思考を晴らして
The stars traced arcs again, clearing my hazy thoughts.
「いつかまた会える」 なんて言えなかった
I couldn't even say, "We'll meet again someday."
星が降ったあとの街、僕はまだ 黒くくすんだがらんどうの空を
In the town after the falling stars, I'm still gazing at the dark, hollow sky...
煌星が彩るように 君を刺した不安も苦痛も
as sparkling stars decorate it, painting over your pain and anxiety.
僕の青色で塗りつぶして 君の涙をそっと、星の海に流し込むんだ
Gently washing your tears away into the sea of stars.
尾を引いたその光が、誰かをまた救うから
For that trailing light will save someone once again.
SHOULD GO! MY LOVE! THUNDER GLOW
for YOU RIDE ACROSS THE BLUE
ラセンを描く ゆれてる DESIRE
Tracing spirals, a swaying desire.
いい子でいるのが 鏡の世界なら馬鹿らしい
If being a good girl in a world of mirrors is wise, how foolish.
火花逃げ こわれることを恐れていた
Sparks escaping, fearing they'd break.
そう 導火線を隠していた
Yes, I had hidden the fuse.
ビリビリ震えている 水面! 夢を! 溢れさせる 勝負が必要
The water's surface vibrates! Overflowing dreams! Boldness is needed.
シグナル伝えてる 非常・事態!
Signals are transmitting an emergency!
堕天使になるなんて 嘘みたいだね
Becoming a fallen angel sounds like a lie, doesn't it?
双子の宇宙 似ていない 自分が 伝える
A twin universe, unlike myself, is conveying it.
欠けてた パズルを 合わせたら とどろける
When fitted together, the missing puzzle pieces roar.
想いにふたして 優しいふりで ごまかしていた
Covering up my feelings with a gentle facade,
でも くちづけさえ 忘れていた
but I had even forgotten a kiss.
メリメリ高鳴る 肌を! 空を! 破りすすむ ハートは火薬で
Piercing through the throbbing skin and sky, the heart is made of gunpowder!
そのトキ来ている 殻を・割って!
That time has come, shatter the shell!
イナズマ走る 震え 感じたらジャブる
Lightning strikes, feeling the tremor, I throw a jab.
乾いた イタズラ さびつく つようりを
A dry prank, rust-bound bravado,
ヴァイヴァな視線で ナイフに変えよう
let's turn into a knife with vibrant gazes.
無表情を 壊して 忘れていた 鍵を 回すから
Shattering my expression, turning the forgotten key.
思いにふたして 優しいふりで ごまかしていた
Covering up my feelings with a gentle facade,
でも くちづけさえ 忘れていた
but I had even forgotten a kiss.
メリメリ高鳴る 肌を! 空を! 破りすすむ ハートは火薬で
Piercing through the throbbing skin and sky, the heart is made of gunpowder!
そのトキ来ている 殻を・割って!
That time has come, shatter the shell!
イナズマ走る 震え 感じたらジャブる
Lightning strikes, feeling the tremor, I throw a jab.
抱きしめるよ 馬鹿げてるね 過去 あふれ たらば ジャブ
Embracing it, how absurd. Past overflowing, then a jab.
そのとき聴いている 鼓動を割って 鳴り止む走る震え
The heartbeat I'm listening to at that moment shatters, non-stop running tremors...
感じたら 乾いたイタズラ さびつくつよがりを
When I feel them, a dry prank, a rusted bravado...
錆び付く強がりを
rusted bravado...
抜け殻の視線で ナイフに変えよう 表情崩して
Let's turn it into a knife with an empty gaze, breaking our expressions.
表情崩して
Breaking our expressions.
忘れていた 鍵を 回そうから
Turning the forgotten key...
回すから 廻すから ビリビリ震えている
Turning it, turning it, vibrating fiercely...
ビリビリ震えている
vibrating fiercely.
SHOULD GO! MY LOVE! THUNDER GLOW
ラセンを描き ゆれてる DESIRE
Depicting a spiral, a swaying desire
いい子でいるのが 鏡の世界なら馬鹿らしい
It's ridiculous if being a good girl is a mirror world
火花逃げ こわされることを恐れていた
Running from sparks, afraid of breaking apart
そう 導火線を隠していた
Yeah, I was hiding my fuse all along
ビリビリ震えている 水面!
Shuddering on the brink, the water's surface!
夢を! 溢れさせる 勝ち気が必要
To make it overflow, I need determination!
シグナル伝えている 非常・事態!
The signals are telling me: it's an emergency!
堕天使になるなんて 嘘みたいだね
For me to become a fallen angel... seems like a lie
双子の宇宙 似ていない
We're twin cosmos with differing personalities,
自分伝える 欠けていた パズルを 合わせたら
lacking communication, but completing the puzzle...
もっとはやくね その時効いている
Sooner than that, feeling that moment,
体を通って 肌を鳴らして
running through my body, ringing through my skin!
鳴らす 雷走る
Thunder runs through—
震え 感じたらジャズる
When you feel its trembling, jazz out!
抱きしめるよ…
I'll embrace you...
はいっ
Hai!
ということで 皆さん 聴いてくれてありがとうございます！
So everyone, thank you for listening!
星の街のことく現れた明日の原石 VTuberの星街すいせいです！
I'm Hoshimachi Suisei, the VTuber diamond in the rough!
すいちゃーーん！
Suichan!
今日もかわいいー！
You're so cute today too!
ということでちょっとね、お水を飲ませていただきますよ。
So let me drink some water for a moment.
これはみんなに見えない水。
This water is invisible to everyone.
ということでですね、星街すいせい 3月22日で3周年を迎えました。
So, Hoshimachi Suisei celebrated her 3rd anniversary on March 22nd.
あとね、誕生日も3月22日だったんですけども、
And my birthday was also March 22nd,
今日はね、その3周年を記念して、あと生誕祭もやって…
so today, to commemorate that 3rd anniversary and my birthday live...
はい、えっと… こちらにタグが出ていますので、たくさんつぶやいてください！
Yes, um... tags are showing here, so please tweet a lot!
#星街すいせい3周年LIVE 世界トレンド1位になりたい！ お願いしまーす！
"#HoshimachiSuisei3rdAnniversary" I want to be #1 worldwide! Please!
というわけでね、セトリを詰め詰めにしてしまったので、MCの時間があまりないらしいです。
So since the setlist is packed, there's not much MC time (laughs).
というわけで次の曲いっていきたいと思います！いっていきたい、いきたいと思います！
So I'd like to move on to the next song!
次はなんと、あの人がゲストとして来てくれます！
Next, surprisingly, that person is coming as a guest!
それでは次の曲いきましょう――！
Well then, let's go to the next song—!
朝を迎えに行こう
Let's welcome the morning,
眠い目を擦って
rubbing my sleepy eyes.
今日を生きていこう
Let's live today.
baby 悲しまないで
Baby, don't be sad.
迷いそうなら 大きく息を吸って
Take a deep breath if you get lost.
baby 偽らないで 自分を忘れそうなら
Baby, don't be fake, don't forget yourself.
持っているだけの愛なら 分け合えるはずだから
If you only have love, you should share it.
頑張って頑張って 作り上げたモノが
Keep at it, what you built up
簡単に簡単に 壊れても
even if it easily breaks—
笑える朝でいたいな 笑える人でありたいな
I want to laugh in the morning, be someone who can laugh.
baby 着飾らないで ありのままで素敵だと知っているかい?
Baby, don't dress up, aren't you wonderful as you are?
rainy 激しい雨も やがて気付けば晴れている
Rainy, heavy rain soon clears up.
楽しいことが少ないから 批判的になるんだろう?
Is that why you're so critical?
傷ついて傷ついて 隠すしかなかった
Hurt and hurting, hiding was all I could do.
大切な大切な 【本当】も こんな処で亡くすなよ
Don't lose such an important truth here.
頑張って頑張って 作り続けてみよう
Keep at it, let's keep creating.
大切な大切な 【本当】を こんな処で亡くすなよ
Don't lose such an important truth here.
笑える朝を迎えに行こうか 今
Let's go welcome a morning where we can laugh, now.
大切な 大切な
Precious, precious...
本当の音
...true sound.
こんな心で泣くすなよ
Don't cry with a heart like that.
誰もが片意地張ったってない
No matter how stubborn anyone tries to be...
暗く暗い夜ならそろそろ鳴っちゃいそう
In a dark, dark night, it's about to chime.
一人で彷徨うに挟みしたが邪魔をする
Wandering alone, what gets in the way...
見た目を言っていたい
I wanted to keep up appearances.
光は遠く擦れ違っていく
The light passes by far in the distance.
でも
But...
頑張って頑張って作り続けてみよう
Let's keep trying and making things.
大切な 大切な本当の音
Precious, precious, true sound...
こんな心で泣くすなよ
Don't cry with a heart like that.
笑える朝を迎えに行こう今
Let's go welcome a morning we can smile in, right now.
はい、ということで！
Yes, so!
おっしゃー！
Yay!
改めまして、2時3時からはおかゆちゃん来てくれました！
Once again, Toko-chan came to join us!
まいど！戌神ころねです！
Hello! I'm Inugami Korone!
はい、ということで、あの、とこちゃんは、え、あれなんですよ。
Yes, so, um, Toko-chan, well, you see...
去年、12月ソロライブをやまして。
Last year, in December, she had her solo live.
そのときにですね、ゲストで私を呼んでくださったんですよ。
And at that time, she invited me as a guest.
一緒に歌ったり踊ったりね、頑張ったんですけども、ま、それがあったので、私も自分のライブに、とこちゃん呼びたいなと思いまして、呼び返しました。
We sang and danced together, and because of that, I wanted to invite Toko-chan to my own live too, so I invited her back.
呼ばれ返しました！
I got invited back!
めっちゃ秘密にしてたから、多分ね、みんな気づいてなかったの。
I kept it super secret, so probably nobody noticed.
みんな、だって今日、とこちゃんのツイートでさ、「あ、今日やん！みんないないよ！」嘘つきはお前やん！て、じらしじらし、じらしじらしだなと思って。
Everyone, because today in Toko-chan's tweet, she was like, "Ah, it's today! Everyone's not here!" You're the liar! I thought, how teasing.
ええとですね、というわけで、え、次の曲歌って、とこちゃんとはお別れになります。
Uh, so, with that, after singing the next song, we'll be saying goodbye to Toko-chan.
またね、みんな。早い早い。
See you again, everyone. That was fast!
ええとですね、お次に歌う曲は、よるしかさんの曲になります。ちょっと切ない感じの曲ですので、切なめな曲でお別れしたいと思います。
The next song is by Yorushika. It's a melancholic song, so we'd like to say goodbye with a heartfelt song.
はい。気まずい気まずい。気まずいする気あるのかな？痛い。それでは聞いてください、盗作。
Yes. So awkward. Do you even want to make it less awkward? Ouch. Well then, please listen, "Plagiarism".
音楽の切っ掛けは何だっけ 父の持つレコードだったかな
What was it that got me into music? Was it my father's record player?
音を聞くことは気持ちがいい 聞くだけなら努力もいらない
Listening to music feels so good. If you're just listening, you don't even need effort.
前置きはいいから話そう ある時思い付いたんだ
Let's skip the preamble and talk. I had a thought one day.
この歌が僕の物になればこの穴は埋まるだろうか
If this song became mine, would this void be filled?
僕は盗んだ
I stole it.
呻吟 まだ足りない 全部足りない 何一つも満たされない
Still not enough, not enough at all, not a single thing satisfies me.
このまま一人じゃ僕は生きられない
I can't live on all by myself like this.
もっと知りたい 愛を知りたい この心を満たすくらい
I want to know more, I want to know love, enough to fill this heart.
美しいものを知りたい
I want to know beautiful things.
ある時に 街を流れる歌が僕の曲だってことに気が付いた
One day, I realized the song flowing through the town was my own song.
売れたなんて当たり前さ 名作を盗んだものだからさぁ
Of course it sold, because I stole a masterpiece!
彼女も馬鹿だ こいつも馬鹿だ 褒めちぎる奴等は皆馬鹿だ
She's a fool, he's a fool, everyone who praises it to the skies is a fool.
群がる烏合の衆 本当の価値なんてわからずに まぁ それは僕も同じか
A rabble flocking together, not understanding its true value... well, I suppose I'm the same.
僕も同じか
Am I the same too?
母屋から足りない これじゃゲストだろう 少しも満たされない
Not enough from the main house, at this rate I'm just a guest, not satisfied at all.
僕らの言葉 一つじゃ満たされない
Our words alone are not enough to fill it.
愛が知りたい 金が足りない この泥沼を満たすくらい
I want to know love, I need money, enough to fill this mire.
美しいものを知りたい
I want to know something beautiful.
音楽の切っ掛けが何なのか 今じゃもう忘れちまったが
What was the catalyst for music? I've already forgotten by now,
欲じゃないことは覚えてる
but I remember it wasn't about greed.
何か綺麗なものだったな
It must have been something beautiful.
化けの皮なんていつか剥がれる 見向きもされない夜が来る
The mask of disguise will eventually peel off, and a night where no one looks will come.
その時に見られる景色が 心底楽しみで
I'm truly looking forward to the scenery I can see at that time.
そうだ 何一つもなくなって 地位も愛も全部なくなって
That's right, with nothing left at all, status and love all gone,
何もかも失った後に見える夜は本当に綺麗だろうから
the night visible after losing everything will surely be truly beautiful,
本当に 本当に 本当に 綺麗だろうから
truly, truly, truly so beautiful...
僕は盗んだ
I stole it.
ああ まだ足りない もっと感じたい こんな歌じゃ満たされない
Ah, still not enough, I want to feel more, songs like this aren't enough.
君らの場じゃ僕は満たされない
In your place, I am not fulfilled.
まだ知らない 愛を書きたい この心を満たすくらい
I want to write love I don't know yet, enough to fill this heart.
美しいものを知りたい
I want to know something beautiful.
まだ足りない まだ足りない まだ足りない まだ足りない
Still not enough, still not enough, still not enough, still not enough...
まだ足りない 僕も足りない ずっと足りないものが分からない
Still not enough, I'm not enough either, I don't know what's endlessly lacking.
まだ足りない もっと知りたい この体を溶かすくらい
Still not enough, I want to know more, enough to melt this body.
美しい夜を知りたい
I want to know a beautiful night.
冴えない コンクリート
Dull concrete,
君は歩く 僕は一歩後ろから
you walk, and I follow a step behind,
鳴り響く 青の墓
echoing over the blue grave—
黙ってしかなかったと 笑った 君はもういない
laughing, as if I had no choice but to stay silent, you are no longer here.
餓鬼だから 仲間外れ 石ころを蹴飛ばして知らんぷり
Being childish, left out, kicking pebbles and pretending not to notice—
君は前だけを見ていて 僕は君だけを見ていた
you were looking straight ahead, while I was only looking at you.
朝焼けと夕焼けの色彩を仰いだ 淀まりの色彩を
I looked up at the colors of sunrise and sunset, and the stagnant hues—
仕方ないな と一つ繋ぎ目
"It can't be helped," connecting them as one,
昨日見た夢と 今日も言いついた空騒ぎ 喉に乾いた爪痕
yesterday's dream and today's commotion, scratch marks dried in my throat.
君は明日へ歩いていった
You walked toward tomorrow—
冴えない コンクリート 僕はここで立ち止まったまま ささやいた
Dull concrete, I stayed stopped right here and whispered.
あの日 新しい上履きの
That day, stepping on the heels of my new indoor shoes,
踵を踏んで コンパスの針を 腕に突き立てた
I pierced my arm with the needle of a compass.
あの日 いなくなりたいと 願っていたのに 2センチも背が伸びた
That day, though I wished to disappear, I grew two centimeters taller.
あの日 許せない 許せないと 自転車を漕いで 息を切れさせた
That day, telling myself I couldn't forgive it, I rode my bicycle and lost my breath.
あの日…
That day...
あの日 ぼくはぼくから旅立った
That day, I set off on a journey from myself.
ぼくのいない明日が今日になる ぼくがいた昨日は昨日のままで
Tomorrow, without me, becomes today. Yesterday, where I was, remains just yesterday.
あの空の下ですずづいている
It continues beneath that sky.
ぼくは通り過ぎる 雨雲みたいに きみの顔を曇らせて きみの不幸を祈る
Like passing rainclouds, I cloud your face and pray for your misfortune.
あの日 学校の中庭で 朝顔が咲いた
That day, morning glories bloomed in the school courtyard,
悔やむように 白い花が咲いた
As if regretting it, white flowers bloomed.
あの日 よく芯が折れる鉛筆で 手紙を書いた
That day, I wrote a letter with a pencil whose lead easily breaks,
さようならとだけ書いた
Writing only "goodbye."
あの日 貯金箱を割って 切符を買った
That day, I broke open my piggy bank and bought a ticket,
行ったことのない 駅で降りた
And got off at a station I had never been to.
あの日…
That day...
あの日 ぼくはぼくから旅立った
That day, I set off on a journey from myself.
ぼくのいない明日が今日になる
Tomorrow, without me, becomes today.
ぼくがいた昨日は昨日のままで あの空の下ですずづいている
Yesterday, where I was, remains just yesterday, continuing beneath that sky.
ぼくは照らし返す 夕日みたいに きみの顔を照らして きみの幸せを祈る
Like a reflecting sunset, I illuminate your face and pray for your happiness.
きみの幸せを祈る
I pray for your happiness.
ぼくの髪を撫でたきみは
The hair I touched that day,
きみの腕を掴んだぼくは
Using your arm,
ぼくの耳に触れたきみは きみの背中にしがみついたぼくは
The me who clung to your back...
あの時 一番温かかったぼくらは
Was the warmest I had ever been at that time.
もういない
No longer...
あの日 ぼくはぼくから旅立った
That day, I set off on a journey from myself.
ぼくのいない明日が今日になる
Tomorrow, without me, becomes today.
ぼくがいた昨日は昨日のままで
Yesterday, where I was, remains just yesterday.
Wow! Wow! Wow!
Raise voice! Shout out!!!
Raise voice! Shout!!!
No way?!
なんにもさないまま ただ死ぬなんて such a fool!
Living half-heartedly and dying like that is such a fool!
まだまだ終わらせないな show me now!
I won't let it end yet, show me now!
世界トレンド1位ありがとうございます！
Thank you for #1 trending worldwide!
ココロの芯から 舌を舐めずり
Licking my lips deep down from the abyss of the heart
暗い呪文並べて Aiming for…
Dark incantation is what we are aiming for
笑顔で凶暴さを Calm down たしなめて
Calm the madness with a smile now obey me
仮面を取り替え引っ替えやりやってる
Disguised in a different mask every day
Show time!
Hi★What happened?
Hi★ What happened?
常になんかのシンドロームでドロッロ
Affected by some syndrome causing destruction
安心?(NO!) 平常心?(NO!)
At ease? (No!) Peace of mind? (No!)
いつまでやってんの? おヒマなんですかね?
How long can you keep this up? Are you really that bored?
Listen with attention…
Let's ブチ壊して
Let's wreck and destroy it
(Countdown 3, 2, 1)
Ready go!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ暴き出せ(EVERYBODY)
From this moment, it is time to expose everything (Everybody)
獣みたいに叫べよ You can change your world!
Screaming through the beast that’s locked up inside
僕たちの歌で“Welcome to US”
This is our song follow our voice “Welcome to US”
Let it go…Let it go…Let it go…
Let it go… Let it go… Let it go…
(Get your gun! Let’s shoot! Bang! Bang!)
笑止千万 撃ち砕け!
Crush this ridiculous nonsense!
(Get your gun! Let’s shoot! Bang! Bang!)
偽善者たちよ バイバイ
Fake hypocrites, say your goodbye
お口を開けば 噴き出すモヤモヤ
Every time you open your mouth, irritating sounds are all I hear
不平不満 罵詈雑言 etc…
Acting like a victim in this unfair world
育てていたんだ Do you know? いつの間に
It’s building up day by day
花火が踊り出し ハシャグ
Do you know? Out of nowhere fire sparks
Show time!
Hi★Are you all right?
Hi★ Are you all right?
得意の言い訳を並べてイイわね?
Once again you’re gonna spit those useless excuses
大事?(NO!) 一大事?(NO!)
Crucial (No!) Very crucial (No!)
よく飽きないな コッチ人はもう飽きちまってんの
How are you not tired cuz I’m so tired of it
Listen with attention…
前にならえに
We gotta fall in line
(Countdown 3, 2, 1)
ナ・ラ・ウ・ナ!
Don’t waste your time!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ解き放て(EVERYBODY)
From this moment, it is time to release everything (Everybody)
獣みたいに 隠さずに You can change your world!
Unleash the beast that’s locked up inside
僕たちの歌で“Welcome to US”
This is our song, follow our voice “Welcome to US”
己の意味 示せよ(I say, You say, We say)
Prove your existence now, and show them who you are
“ココ”で(I say, You say, We say)
From here on (I say, You say, We say)
快進撃のChance
Move forward, grasp the chance
(Countdown 3, 2, 1)
Ready go!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ暴き出せ(EVERYBODY)
From this moment, it is time to expose everything (Everybody)
獣みたい 正直に You can change your world!
Stay true like the beast that’s locked up inside
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ暴き出せ(EVERYBODY)
From this moment, it is time to expose everything (Everybody)
獣みたいに叫べよ You can change your world!
Screaming through the beast that’s locked up inside
僕たちの歌で“Welcome to US”
This is our song follow our voice “Welcome to US”
Let it go…Let it go…Let it go…
Let it go… Let it go… Let it go…
(Get your gun! Let’s shoot! Bang! Bang!)
笑止千万 撃ち砕け!
Crushing this ridiculous nonsense!
(Get your gun! Let’s shoot! Bang! Bang!)
偽善者たちよ バイバイ
Fake hypocrites, say your goodbye
Don't run away!
Don’t run away!
Mark my words!
Hang in there. It's up to you. (Don't run away!)
世界を創り出したのは
Creating the world...
お前の本気のぶっ超えだけ
It's all about your serious breakthrough...
Never say never break it
一度きりなら 後悔せず生き抜け
If it's only once, live through it without regrets!
Never say never break it
Come on break it out
お前なりの自分らしく In low
Stay true to yourself in your own way
おかしなこと人生は
Life is such a funny thing
Make some noise!
Wow...
SHOUTOUT
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
今…ホロライブバンド解散してしまいました！
Now... the Hololive Band has disbanded!
それが私たち、エアーズ！
That's us, Airz!
エアーズ解散してしましたが、なんと次の曲で解散となります！
Airz disbanded, but surprisingly we'll disband again on the next song!
はい、ということで最後の曲聴いてください。EXPOSE Burn out!!!
So, please listen to our final song. EXPOSE Burn out!!!
EXPOSE 'Burn out!!!'
Let's go!
ココロの淵から 舌を舐めずり
From the depths of the heart, licking my lips,
暗い呪文並べて Aiming for
lining up dark incantations, aiming for...
笑顔で凶暴性を Calm down たしなめて
Calming down the wildness with a smile,
仮面を取り換え引っ換えやってる
changing masks over and over.
Show time!
Hi! What happened?
常に何かのシンドロームでドロドロ
Always falling into some syndrome,
安心?(NO!)平常心?(NO!)
at ease? (No!) Peace of mind? (No!)
いつまでやってんの?お暇なんですか?
How long are you gonna keep this up? Are you really that bored?
Listen with attention...
Let'sぶち壊して
Let's smash it to pieces!
(Countdown 3,2,1) Ready go!
(Countdown 3, 2, 1) Ready go!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ曝け出せ(EVERYBODY)
Expose everything right now, everybody!
獣みたいに叫べよ You can change your world!
Scream like a beast, you can change your world!
僕たちの歌で“Welcome to US”
With our song, "Welcome to US"!
Let it go...Let it go...Let it go...
Let it go... Let it go... Let it go...
(Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!)
笑止千万 撃ち砕け!
Crush all that nonsense!
(Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!)
偽善者たちよ バイバイ
Goodbye, you hypocrites!
口を開けば 吹き出すモヤモヤ
When you open your mouth, irritation pours out,
不平不満愚痴雑言 etc...
filled with complaints and grumbling.
育んでいたんだ Do you know? いつの間にか
Do you know? Before you knew it,
火花が踊りだし騒がしぐ
sparks began to dance and cause a ruckus.
Show time!
Hi! Are you all right?
お決まりの良い訳を並べて いいわね?
Lining up the same old excuses, aren't you?
重大?(NO!)重大?(NO!)
Crucial? (No!) Very crucial? (No!)
よくあきないなこっちもうあきちゃってんだ
How are you not tired of this? I'm already so sick of it.
Listen with attention...
前に習えに
Fall in line!
(Countdown 3,2,1) 習えな!
(Countdown 3, 2, 1) Fall in line!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ解き放て(EVERYBODY)
Release everything right now, everybody!
獣みたいに恥じずに You can change your world!
Unleash the beast inside without shame, you can change your world!
僕たちの歌で“Welcome to US”
With our song, "Welcome to US"!
お前の意味 示せよ(I say, You say, We say)
Show them what you really mean right here!
“ここ”で(I say, You say, We say)
(I say, You say, We say)
Listen with attention...
会心撃のチャンス
Seize the chance,
(Countdown 3,2,1) Ready go!
(Countdown 3, 2, 1) Ready go!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ暴きだせ(EVERYBODY)
Unleash everything right now, everybody!
獣みたいに正直に You can change your world!
Stay true like a beast, you can change your world!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ曝け出せ(EVERYBODY)
Expose everything right now, everybody!
獣みたいに叫べよ You can change your world!
Scream like a beast, you can change your world!
僕たちの歌で“Welcome to US”
With our song, "Welcome to US"!
Let it go...Let it go...Let it go...
Let it go... Let it go... Let it go...
(Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!)
笑止千万 撃ち砕け!
Crush all that nonsense!
(Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!)
偽善者たちよ バイバイ
Goodbye, you hypocrites!
(Don't run away!)Don't run away!
(Don't run away!) Don't run away!
Mark my words!
暴れだせ
Hang in there. It's up to you.
(Don't run away!)
獣みたいに今すぐ 解き放て
Hang in there. It's up to you.
(Don't run away!)
獣みたいに事実にと
Hang in there. It's up to you.
(Don't run away!)
僕たちの歌で“Welcome to US”
Hang in there. It's up to you.
(Don't run away!)
頭振り続け
Head banging!
踊り狂いなさい!
Don't stop dancing!
無能の意味 さし示せよ
Show the true meaning of the number one,
ここで
Right here!
(I say, You say, We say)
Listen with attention...
会心撃のチャージ
The counter-attack charge!
(Countdown 3,2,1) Ready go!
(Countdown 3, 2, 1) Ready go!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ暴きだせ(EVERYBODY)
Unleash everything right now, everybody!
暴れ出せ
Rampage like a beast, you can change your world!
獣みたい正直に You can change your world!
Stay honest like a beast, you can change your world!
Mark my words!
何もかも 今すぐ曝け出せ(EVERYBODY)
Expose everything right now, everybody!
獣みたいに叫べよ You can change your world!
Scream like a beast, you can change your world!
僕たちの歌で“Welcome to US”
With our song, "Welcome to US"!
Let it go...Let it go...Let it go...
Let it go... Let it go... Let it go...
(Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!)
笑止千万 撃ち砕け!
Crush all that nonsense!
(Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!)
偽善者たちよ バイバイ
Goodbye, you hypocrites!
Let it go...Let it go...
Let it go... Let it go...
Let it go...
Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!
笑止千万 撃ち砕け!
Crush all that nonsense!
Get your gun! Let's shoot! Bang! Bang!
偽善者たちよ バイバイ
Goodbye, you hypocrites!
Don't run away!
4th YOUTUBE LIVE SPACE for Virtual GHOST
ようこそ、星街すいせい4th YouTube Liveへ！
Welcome to Hoshimachi Suisei's 4th YouTube Live!
空っぽの手の平と無垢なまなざし
With empty palms and an innocent gaze,
芳しくない空想に身を任せていた
letting myself yield to dreary fantasies.
今この宇宙に背を向けて 日が昇るまでの時間で
Turning my back on this universe now, in the time until the sun rises,
漂うままに踊らせて
let me dance as I drift along.
詰まらないような明日が来ても
Even if a dull tomorrow comes,
笑顔で着飾って過ごせるように
so I can dress it up with a smile,
魔法をちょちょだいなんてさ
asking for magic like, "give me some."
埋まらないような心があるの
There's a heart that can never be filled,
浮かべた非日常が降り注ぐ
shower it with an unwonted everyday magic,
ほつれない魔法をかけて
cast an unfraying spell.
ひとりきり 騒がしいネオン街の中
Alone, amidst the bustling neon streets,
背伸びしたピンヒールが折れそうなステップ
steps on tiptoe in stiletto heels about to snap.
今この街に踏み入れて 日が昇るまでの時間で
Stepping into this town now, in the time until the sun rises,
朧気に踊らせて
let me dance faintly.
変わらないような明日が来たの
An unchanging tomorrow has arrived,
指先が静かに空を切って またいつもの朝焼け
my fingertips quietly slice the sky once more at dawn's glow.
がらんどうな心がいちど求めた非日常が降り注ぐ
The extraordinary that my hollow heart once desired pours down,
ほつれない魔法をかけて
cast an unfraying spell.
ヘッドライトで照らし出されているデビュタント
A debutante illuminated by headlights,
ひび割れかけのざらついているアスファルトステージ
on a cracked, rough asphalt stage.
午前0時前のドラマは始まらないまま
The drama before midnight remains unstarted,
魔法を ねぇ
magic... hey,
魔法をかけて
cast a spell.
笑顔を着脱して過ごせるように
So I can put on and take off smiles as I live,
運命を投げ捨てて
casting fate aside,
埋まらないような心があるの
there's a heart that can never be filled,
求められた非日常が降り注ぐ
shower it with the requested extraordinary,
ほつれない魔法をかけて
cast an unfraying spell.
Cast an unfraying spell.
今月の下で待ち合わせ 全部準備が全然終わんないよ
Meeting under the moonlight, none of my prep is ready at all!
会いたい すぐに会いたい
I want to see you, I want to see you right now,
焦る気持ちを沈めなきゃ
I've gotta calm this hurried feeling down!
どうしようび
What should I wear?
歌いたい歌は希望
The song I want to sing is hope,
よしこれで大丈夫
alright, is this okay?
エビバディレッツゴー
Everybody let's go!
眠れない夜にさようなら
Farewell to sleepless nights,
夢であなたと逢える夢ドリーム
meeting you in my dreams, dream, dream!
愛ジャンプでにらめっこ
Staring contest with a jump of love,
後ろの方まで全部見えてるよ
I can see all the way to the back rows!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
君との果てまで止まらないでずっと
Keep going endlessly with you, never stopping!
遠くまで歩こうよ 裸足で
Let's walk far away, barefoot,
小さな幸せを見つけて
finding small happiness.
湿った月が窓を覗いて
A damp moon peeks through the window
こっちへおいでって笑った
and smiled, saying "come over here."
Dancing in the moonlight
月の光 感じて
feeling the moonlight's glow.
Dancing in the moonlight
このリズムを 止められない
I can't stop this rhythm.
イー
Ooh...
Dancing in the moonlight
聞かせてあげる ミュージック
I'll let you hear the music.
覚悟しててね
Be prepared.
Dancing in the moonlight
この光インサイド
this light inside...
死なく輝いて どこまでも歌う声は
Shining endlessly, the singing voice echoes everywhere.
Dancing in the moonlight
ゲイ ゲイ
Yeah, yeah...
ワン オー ワン オー
One on one, one on one...
Dancing in the moonlight
少年ブレイヴ
[Song: Shounen Brave]
いじめないで ネトを泣かせてばかり
Stop bullying me, leaving me crying on the net.
震えちゃうのも 仕方ないです
It's only natural that I'm trembling.
孤独を 定期に恐れてる
Regularly fearing loneliness,
少年の僕の 勇気は嫌った
my boyish courage hated it.
同じように雨を濡れてる
Getting soaked in the same rain,
自分勝手に 抱き寄せてた
holding me close selfishly.
「君は僕を いじめないよね」って言って
Saying, "You won't bully me, right?"
友達になろう 言葉じゃないところでさ
Let's be friends, somewhere beyond words.
話がしたいような そんな僕に悲劇が待ってた
A tragedy awaited a me who wanted to talk like that.
聞こえたんだ 声が世代に 覗いたの ノックする
I heard a voice knocking, peering into the generation.
「あいつは汚い」そいつをだまそう大嫌い 死んじゃえなんて
"That guy is filthy," "Let's trick him," "I hate you," "Drop dead,"
想いの声が一斉に こばんでいたってノックする
the chorus of thoughts was echoing all at once, knocking.
言葉にしない 心が突き刺さっても泣きそう
Even if an unspoken heart pierces me, I feel like crying.
希望を願ったばっさって 曇ものそうわ 僕にこんな代償を埋め込んでた
Wishing for hope... burying such a price inside me.
そして今日も 声が響き渡る
And today too, the voice echoes across.
流れ込んで 僕を狂わして 人の心を 吸い取れる
Flowing in, driving me crazy, able to absorb human hearts.
こんなの僕を 誰よりも嫌った
Hating this kind of me more than anyone,
逃げ出そうと 外へ飛び出せ
I try to escape, dashing outside.
ここじゃもう いいこできないから
Because I can't be a good boy here anymore.
立ち直ぞう 目を背けてさ
I'll stand back up, turning my eyes away,
僕をそっと 駆け出したぞう
and started running away softly.
迷い込むのり息のない静けさに また怯えちゃうような
Wandering into a breathless silence, startling once again.
そんな僕を 誰かが待ってた聞こえたんだ 今日も淡々と
Someone was waiting for a me like that, I heard today too, calmly.
描いた 今日を待ってるの 誰かお願い どこから助け出してよ
Waiting for the painted day, someone please, rescue me from somewhere.
寂しいようななんて 想いの声は順々にな
Thoughts like "How lonely" are orderly...
昨日の僕のようなんだ 心がこわい 明日を変える勇気も足りない
Like my yesterday, my heart is scared, I lack the courage to change tomorrow.
「いじめないでよ」ってないてばかり
"Leave me alone," I cried, "And please quit teasing me!"
ふるえてしまうのもしかたがないのです
Shivering up and down, I couldn't do a thing
こどくをびんかんににおそれている
Why am I so afraid of being left behind?
しょうねんのぼくをゆうきはきらってた
Sometimes I think that "bravery" just doesn't like me
おなじようにあめにぬれている
We were the same, a dog abandoned in the rain
こいぬにりかいをもとめていた
Reaching a hand, I begged for him to know my pain
じぶんかちきにだきよせていた
Holding him tight, I whispered shaking in the night
「きみはぼくをいじめないよね？」っていって
"You're different, right? You won't bully me and things will be alright"
「ともだちになろう
"How 'bout you and me be friends?"
ことばじゃないところでさ、はなしがしたいよな」
"Though we'll never have to use any words"
そんなぼくにとひびきがたまってた
Such a tragedy was knocking at my door
きこえたんだこえがせいかいに、とざしたのうをのっくする
I heard it loud and soon had come to find
「あいつはきたいない」「そいつをだますう」「だいたい」「しんじょうえ」なんて
Voices that knocked and rattled at my mind
おもいのこえがこせきに、こぼんでいたってのっくする
They just won't hear me, listen, or try
ことばにしないところがつきささって、もうなきそう
Not a word to swallow left me feeling hollow, if I can't talk, then I'll cry!
「きぼうをねがったばくだ」って、こどくもうのそうんは
Well this is what you get for holding on
ぼくになんなだいしょうを、うおそんていた
And buried this in me because "It's eye for eye"
そしてきょうもこえはせせめてる、ながれこんでぼくはとかしていく
And so everyday, the same they're cloudy minds will rain
ひとのしんりをすすみとれる、めうようなぼくをだれかがきらった
Soaking me through, I start to break and melt away
にげだそうとそとへおうちびだす、ここじゃもういきもできないから
Running away, I thought I could maybe escape
まちのぞうおうのめをさけてさ、ぼくはおそっくかけだしたけどかへろ
Standing in place would only make me suffocate
まよいうこうもり、いきばのないしずけさに、またおびえちゃうような
Dodging the daggers from their eyes and brushed aside
そんなぼくをだれかがまっていた、きこえたんだ「きょうもたんたんと」
I flew away and out of their sight to where they couldn't find
えがいたきょうをまっている、の誰かおねがい、ここから、たすけだししてほしいよ」なんて
Circling the woods, I know is crazy
どれくらい 歩いて きたんだろう
How long did it take me to get this far
怯えて 過ごす 毎日だった
I spent every day afraid
勘違い 我儘 太刀 僕らを 引き裂いてた
Selfish misunderstandings, the strike of a sword that tore us apart
散々 眺めた 夢の続きが そうさ 傷跡に 塩を塗り込んでく
When I think about the dream, it's like pouring salt on a wound
だから僕は 待って 待って 未来を待って 立って
So I will be waiting, waiting for you
ずっと 生きてるって 感じてたかったから
Because I wanted to always feel like I'm alive
きっと めぐり会った僕らは奇跡なんだ
Surely we met each other in a miracle
どれだけ 話せば 分かってくれる？
How much more do I have to say before you understand?
don't you think every time ェビターン あの空を 染めてけ
Don't you think every time, paint that sky, promise the star
どれくらい 立ち止まっただろう 怯えて 過ごす 毎日だった
How long have I been standing still? I spent every day afraid
迷っては 戻る 過去たちが 僕らを 追い越してく
Memories that hesitate and turn back overtake us
変わらない 思いを もっと 見せれたら いい なだ って
I wish I could show you my unchanging feelings more
散々 眺めた 夢の続きが そうさ 茜さす 日々を 照らしてく
When I think about the dream, it illuminates those madder-red days
ずっと これだけって 思ってきたんだから
Because I've always thought only this much
だから君を 待って 待って 未来を待って 立って
So I will be waiting, waiting for you
絶対 約束された ものなんか ないんだから 答えは 神様だけが 知ってる
There is absolutely nothing promised, only God knows the answer
ふと 気付けば すぐそばに 僕と最高が 誓いを 満たす まで
When I suddenly realize you're right beside me and the best until our oath is fulfilled
だから 僕は 待って 待って 未来を 待って 立って
So I will be waiting, waiting for you
ずっと 生きてるって 感じてたかったから
Because I wanted to always feel like I'm alive
きっと めぐり会った僕らは奇跡なんだ
Surely we met each other in a miracle
どれだけ 話せば 分かってくれる？
How much more do I have to say before you understand?
don't you think every time エビターン あの空を 染めてけ
Don't you think every time, paint that sky, promise the star
だから僕は待って
So I will wait, wait
待って 未来を待って
Wait, waiting for the future
立って
Standing
ずっと生きてるって感じてたから
Because I felt like I've been living all along
だから君を待って 待って
So waiting for you, waiting
未来を待って 待って
Waiting for the future, waiting
きっと巡り合った僕らは
Surely the two of us who crossed paths
奇跡なんだ
are a miracle
どれだけ話せばわかってくれる?
How much must I speak for you to understand?
don't you think every time
あの空を染めていけ
dye that sky
途中でびたん エビタイム 瞳閉じて
don't you think every time, close your eyes
途中でびたん エビタイム あの空を
don't you think every time, that sky
染めていけ
dye it red
プロミスザスター
Promise the Star
はぁ
Hah...
えぇ皆さん
Um, everyone,
お疲れ様です お水飲ませてください
thank you for your hard work. Let me drink some water.
あぁ
Ah,
すみません 途中でなんか
sorry, in the middle, um
あの 機材トラブルが起こって あの 配信におけるすべての機材が あの シャットアウトするという
equipment trouble happened, and all the equipment for the stream shut down
マジでびっくりした 本当にすみません
I was really surprised, I'm truly sorry!
それでも見てくれてるみんな本当にありがとうございます
Even so, thank you all so much for watching.
ちょっと焦りすぎてしまったんですが
I panicked a bit, but...
あ そうそうそうだ あの これすごくない?
Ah, that's right, isn't this amazing?
ゴンドラ 私が運営さんにわがまま言ってつけてもらいました!
The gondola! I selfishly asked management to put it on for me!
ゴンドラすごいでしょう? みんなのこと もうみんな見えてる
The gondola is amazing, right? I can see everyone!
もうみんな見えてる ありがとう!
I can see everyone, thank you!
はい ということで
So, um
次は まだあるんです なんと まだ歌うんです
Next, there's still more—surprisingly, I'm still going to sing!
次は オリジナル曲を歌っていきたいと思います
Next, I'd like to sing an original song.
えっと このライブ限定のスペシャルバージョンになっていますので
Um, since this is a special version exclusive to this live,
ぜひぜひ最後まで、最後まで見ていってください よろしくお願いします
please be sure to watch all the way to the end! Thank you very much.
それでは行きましょう!
Now then, let's go!
あの空で輝いた 流星を追いかけて
Chasing the shooting star that shone in that sky
いつか君を照らすから
Someday it will illuminate you
彗星のスターライト
Comet Starlight
生まれたばかりの小さな光は
The tiny light that was just born
消えてしまいそうな声で歌ったんだ
sang in a voice that seemed as if it might vanish
誰かに届くように そうその声を振り絞って
Straining that voice so that it would reach someone
いまはまだ響かないとしても いつかそのこころに
Even if it doesn't resonate yet, someday to that heart...
響く声は眠れないほどに胸を打たせて
The resonating voice makes my heart beat so much I can't sleep
あたしのこと見ていてね
Please look at me
彗星の歌は
The comet's song...
天球、彗星は夜を跨いで
Celestial Sphere, the Comet Straddles the Night
まだまだ終われない 最後まで盛り上がっていけるよな!
We're not done yet! Can you get hyped all the way to the end?!
光がひとつ灯った 燈った 天を彩った霓が綺麗だ
A single light was lit, lit. The rainbow adorning the sky is beautiful
明かりがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on, flickered on.
天を彩った雫が綺麗だ
The drops adorning the heavens are so beautiful.
僕の吐いた白い息のように 消してしまえたらな
If I could erase them like my own white breath...
押し殺して深く沈んだ 泣き声さえ 聴こえているから
Suppressing it, sinking deep down, even your cries, because I can hear them.
君を刺した不安も苦悩も 僕の青色で塗り潰して
Painting over the anxiety and pain that pierced you with my blue hue,
全部涙になって 星の海を流れていった
and turning it all into tears, flowing into the sea of stars.
果てしない闇の中に そっと青を添えたら ほら
If I gently add blue into the endless darkness, look,
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
A comet flew right above my head,
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
dyeing the empty night sky.
深く寝静まった街の中へ 降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Into the deeply slumbering town, whose sorrow is pouring down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The comet flew again, drawing an arc,
もやのかかった思考を晴らして
clearing away the hazy thoughts.
「いつかまた会える」なんて言えなかった
I couldn't say "We'll meet again someday."
星が降ったあとの街、僕はまだ
In the town after the stars fell, I'm still...
ずっと君のゆくえを探してた
endlessly searching for where you went.
星が揺らいで 目を見ている
Stars are swaying, watching my eyes,
焦がれたその音が待っているの
that yearning sound is waiting for us.
キラめくカラー 決めている日々に 伝えるこのメロディ
In days deciding shimmering colors, I deliver this melody.
窓から覗いた 雨の降る街並みを
Gazing out the window at the rain-drenched cityscape,
弾ける音だから ポケットに詰め込んで Let's dance now
it's a bouncing sound, so let's pack it in our pockets and let's dance now.
君の好きな (ちょっとcoolでpopなparty song)
Your favorite (a little cool and pop party song)
キラチューンのステップに乗せて
riding on the steps of a glittering tune.
魔法のような (もっとvivid passion shiny ray)
Like magic (more vivid passion shiny ray),
ライトが私を照らしている
the lights are illuminating me.
星を紡いで 夢を描くよ
Weaving the stars, painting a dream,
焦がれたその声が呼んでいるの
that yearning voice is calling out.
キラめくカラー まとった君に
To you, draped in shimmering colors,
届けるこのメロディ
I deliver this melody.
このままじゃね終われない (終われない)
We can't just end it like this (we can't)
SpecialなStage 踊り明かすの (明かそう)
dancing the night away on a special stage (let's light it up).
このままじっとしてられない (そうさせない)
We can't just stay still like this (won't let you)
走り出そうよ 明日は晴れるから
Let's start running, because tomorrow will be clear.
まだ目が覚めない カーテンを開けても
Even if you open the curtains still half-asleep,
憂鬱そうだと コメントが流れたら Let's show now
if gloomy comments flow by, let's show now.
いつも着ていた (ちょっとtrend baseなgirly style)
Changing out of the clothes you always wore
ショーウィンドウの服着替えて
into a slightly trend-based girly style in the shop window.
魔法のような (ちょっとcoolでpopなparty time)
Like magic (a little cool and pop party time),
ドレスがふわりっひるがえる
your dress flutters and billows softly.
満天の星空にほら 浮かべてみて明日のビジョン
Just look, float tomorrow's vision in the starry sky.
そこで見える そこで見えるなら もっと飛べるよ
If you can see it there, if you can see it there, you can fly even higher.
満開の笑顔ならほら 歌ってみてこのトキメキ
With a full-blossoming smile, just try singing this excitement.
そこで会える そこで会えるから だってきっと世界は変わるから！
Because we'll meet there, because we'll meet there—surely the world will change!
星を紡いで 夢を描くよ
Weaving the stars, painting a dream,
焦がれたその声が呼んでいるの
that yearning voice is calling out.
キラめくカラー まとった君に 届けるこのメロディ
To you, draped in shimmering colors, I deliver this melody.
このままじゃね終われない (終われない)
We can't just end it like this (we can't)
SpecialなStage 踊り明かすの (明かそう)
dancing the night away on a special stage (let's light it up).
このままじっとしてられない (そうさせない)
We can't just stay still like this (won't let you)
走り出そうよ 世界は変わるから
Let's start running, because the world will change.
パッと弾けた感情に 言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my days lining up excuses for my bursting emotions.
葛藤も知らない街明かり 君だけだって嘘をついた
Under city lights oblivious to my struggles, I lied and said it was only you.
信じたくないままで踊っている 示すために続けた言葉
Dancing without wanting to believe, continuing to string words together to prove it.
見えないの 僕は僕のこの声が聞こえている?
Can you not see? Can my voice be heard by myself?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすら透明で きっと不格好だけれどでも
Even my silhouette is transparent, surely clumsy though it may be.
せめて声を枯らそう 必死に絡んでもずっと証明を
Let me at least strain my voice, desperately clinging to prove it always.
ねぇ GHOST みたいだ
Hey, I feel like a ghost.
散々恨んだ明るさと 意味ありげに伸びていく影
Resenting the brightness I cursed so much, shadows stretch out meaningfully.
淡々と過ぎた一粒の 君の言葉で泣きたくなった
A single, calmly passing word from you made me want to cry.
大事に遺したいものが零れていく 示すままに縋り続けたい言葉
Things I want to cherish are slipping away, words I want to keep clinging to as shown.
見えているのか 僕のこの声が届いている?
Can you see? Is this voice of mine reaching you?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすら透明で きっと不格好だけれどだから
Even my silhouette is transparent, clumsy though it is, and that's why
叫んで足掻いて 裸足のままで走って
I scream, I struggle, and I keep running barefoot.
パッと弾けた感情に
In the burst of emotions,
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my time making excuses.
葛藤も知らない街明かり
City lights oblivious to my struggles,
君だけだって嘘をついた
I lied, saying it was only you.
ねぇ ゴーストみたいだ
Hey, I look like a ghost.
さんざん呪った 明るさと
Resenting the brightness,
意味ありげに伸びていく影
Shadows stretching meaningfully.
淡々と過ぎた ひとつの
A single, calmly passing
君の言葉で泣きたくなった
Word from you made me want to cry.
大切にしたいものがこぼれていく
Things I want to cherish are spilling away.
示すままに綴り続けたい言葉
Words I want to keep spelling out as shown.
見えてるの 僕が僕の
Can you see me? Can you hear
この声が聴こえている？
my voice, the voice of who I am?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすら透明で きっと不格好だけれど
Even my silhouette is transparent, surely clumsy,
せめて声を枯らそう 必死に足掻いても
Let me at least strain my voice, struggling desperately
ずっと証明を
to keep proving it.
ねぇ ゴーストみたいだ
Hey, I feel like a ghost.
だから叫んで足掻いて 裸足のまま走って
So I scream, struggle, and run barefoot.
ねぇ 気付いて 教えてよ 答えは
Hey, notice me, tell me the answer.
こんな僕の心まで馬鹿にしないで
Don't make a mockery of even my heart.
灰色の街が喋ってる
The gray city is murmuring.
足取りも重くなる
My steps are growing heavier too.
声を枯らして叫んで足掻いて 裸足で走り続けて
Straining my voice, screaming, running barefoot,
変わらないように 諦めないように 連ね続けるだけだ
Just keeping on stringing words so I won't change or give up.
見つけてよ 僕が僕のこの声が聴こえている？
Find me. Can you hear my voice, the voice of who I am?
Dancer in the dark シルエットすら透明で
Dancer in the dark, even my silhouette is transparent,
きっと不格好だけれど
surely clumsy, but still
せめて声を枯らそう 必死に足掻いても
Let me at least strain my voice, struggling desperately
ずっと証明を
to keep proving it.
ねぇ ゴーストみたいだ
Hey, I feel like a ghost.
新曲「GHOST」ミュージックビデオこのあとすぐ深夜0時プレミア公開！
New single "GHOST" music video premiering tonight right after midnight!
星街すいせい 誕生日の活動三周年記念 4月13日販売開始
Hoshimachi Suisei Birthday & 3rd Anniversary Goods on sale April 13!
星街すいせいデザイン「星型リングライト」
Hoshimachi Suisei design "Star-shaped Ring Light"
4th YOUTUBE LIVE SPACE for Virtual GHOST